Guide to the Vassar College Realia Collection, circa 1648-2020 (bulk 1818-2000)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Realia Collection
circa 1648 - 2020
1818-2000
Vassar College
45 cubic feet (106 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The collection consists of physical culture materials and objects related to Matthew Vassar, his family, and Vassar College, as well as miscellaneous items of historical note.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of physical culture materials and objects related to Matthew Vassar, his family, and Vassar College, as well as miscellaneous items of historical note.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series: Series I. Vassar Family; Series II. Vassariana; and Series III. Miscellaneous and Historical Objects.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Matthew Vassar Papers
Vassar Family Papers
Vassar College Class Records
Subject Headings
Names:
Booth, Lydia; Booth, Maria Vassar; Vassar, Catherine Valentine; Vassar family; Vassar, Matthew, 1792-1868; Vassar, Matthew, Jr., 1809-1881
Organizations:
Vassar Brewery (Poughkeepsie, N.Y.); Vassar College
Subjects:
Family--New York (State); Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
Object Types:
Academic costume; Badges; Banners; Ceramic ware (visual works); Ceramics (object genre); Clothing; Cylinder phonographs (phonographs); Cylinders (sound recordings); Diplomas; Dresses (garments); Flags; Jewelry; Manual Typewriters; Medals; Mugs (cups); Pennants; Pins (jewelry); Plaques (flat objects); Pocket watches; Porcelain (visual works); Printing plates; Realia; Rings (finger jewelry); Scarves (costume accessories); Sculpture (visual works); Silverware; Stereoscopes; Tableware; Teacups; Textiles (visual works); Tote bags; Toys (recreational artifacts); Transferware; Trophies (objects); T-shirts
VCL Categories:
Audiovisuals and Realia
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, June 2025.
Acquisition Information
Multiple accessions from various sources.
Series List
- Series I. Vassar Family, 1818 - circa 1890
  This series includes objects owned by or affiliated with Matthew Vassar and members of his family.
  Subseries:
  Catherine Vassar
  Lydia Booth
  Margaret (Van Kleeck) Vassar
  Maria Vassar Booth
  Matthew Vassar
  Matthew Vassar, Jr.
  Miscellaneous Family Objects
  Organized into subseries by family member and sub-arranged alphabetically.
- Series II. Vassariana, 1861-2020
  This series includes objects used by, related to, or depicting Vassar College, as well as alumnae/i, faculty, presidents, trustees, and administrators of Vassar College, including artifacts, memorabilia, and souvenirs.
  Accessories
  Awards and Commemorative Objects
  Badges
  Banners and Flags
  Bookmarks
  Ceramics
  Diplomas
  Glass Objects
  Groundbreaking Soil
  Jewelry - Miscellaneous
  Jewelry - Pins
  Jewelry - Rings
  Medals
  Miscellaneous Objects
  Photographs
  Plaques
  Plastic Objects
  Serveware
  Silverware
  Stationary and Paper Items
  Technology
  Toys and Games
  Textiles
  Wooden Objects
  Organized into subseries by object type, sub-arranged alphabetically.
- Series III. Miscellaneous and Historical Objects, circa 1648 - [1917?]
  This series includes various historic objects not directly connected to Vassar College.
  Arranged alphabetically.
Container List
- Series I. Vassar Family Materials, 1818 - circa 1890
  - Catherine Vassar
    - Jewelry, undated (Box 46, Section 07)
      Unidentified piece. Rod-shaped pendant of some kind. Open on one end--possibly broken; set with a yellow stone on the other. Potentially part of the piece in section 5?
    - Jewelry, undated (Box 46, Section 10)
      Unidentified piece, gold. A coil wound around a branch with an empty ring hanging off of it. Appears to be a brooch or pin of some kind, but the piece is not designed to pierce fabric.
    - Jewelry, undated (Box 46, Section 05)
      Unidentified piece. Possibly a necklace. Broken chain with ring-like pendant and stopper-like pendant attached. Both pendants are set with red stones.
    - Jewelry - Cuff link, undated (Box 46, Section 01)
      Gold oval cuff link, engraved with "C.V."
    - Jewelry - Earring, undated (Box 46, Section 08)
      Single earring, gold, pierced
    - Keys (2), undated (Box 46, Section 09)
      2 keys, found in Catherine Vassar's sewing case, do not belong to case
    - Neckerchief, circa 1840 (Box 30)
    - Purse, metal-beaded, undated (Box 30)
    - Sewing case, undated (Box 41)
      Dark wood box with floral inlay on lid, containing a number of silver sewing tools.
  - Lydia Booth
    - Apron, undated (Box 9)
      Lavender-pink, silk print with branching pattern that looks like Christmas lights.
    - Belt, circa 1820 (Box 9)
      Black ribbon belt with floral embroidery (circa 1820) which belonged to Lydia Booth.
    - Jacket, circa 1830 (Box 9)
      Brown and tan plaid taffeta basque (boned, jacket style) with bolero length, wide sleeves.
    - Memorandum case, ivory, undated (Box 23)
    - Shawl, undated (Box 9)
      Ecru, lace. Lydia Booth referred to as "Spanish Lace."
  - Margaret (Van Kleeck) Vassar
    - Apron, 1834 (Box 49)
      Brown waist apron with floral embroidery worn by Matthew Vassar Jr.'s mother, Margaret (Van Kleeck) Vassar.
    - Apron, 1834 (Box 49)
      Pink gingham apron worn by Matthew Vassar Jr.'s mother, Margaret (Van Kleeck) Vassar.
  - Maria Vassar Booth
    - Butter knife, undated (Box 23)
      Silver, initials "MB" Maria Vassar Booth
    - Shawl, undated (Box 9)
      Black, fringed edge. Belonged to Maria Vassar Booth
    - Shawl, undated (Box 9)
      Ecru / white, cotton, ruffled edge with floral embroidery.
  - Matthew Vassar
    - Barrel (2 pieces), undated (Box 1, Section 05)
      Small wooden barrel container. Ends are painted orange.
    - Billfold, undated (Box 1, Section 23)
      Leather billfold.
    - Card case, undated (Box 1, Section 25)
      Leather card case.
    - Carved wooden container (2 pieces), undated (Box 1, Section 04)
      Wooden cylinder-like container with intricate leaf and vine patterns and rounded ends. Screws together in two pieces. Cracked on one half through the threads.
    - Ceramic cup and saucer, undated (Box 4)
      White/cream teacup with a Gold ring painted around the upper edge. Matching saucer.
    - Ceramic nut (2 pieces), undated (Box 1, Section 24)
      Container in the shape of a ceramic nut with top and bottom parts.
    - China plate, undated (Box 20)
      White china plate with blue and gold edging.
    - China saucers (3), undated (Box 20)
      Three white china teacup saucers with blue and gold edging.
    - China teacup, undated (Box 20)
      White china teacup with blue and gold edging.
    - Cigar case, undated (Box 1, Section 26)
      Carved wooden cigar case. Belonged to Matthew Vassar.
    - Dog collar, undated (Box 1, Section 22)
      Rusted chain-link collar. Inscribed plaque reads "Don Vassar."
    - Door lock and handle from Vassar Brewery, undated (Box 34)
      door lock and handle, wood and metal.
    - Envelopes from the Civil War, 1861-1865 (Box 10)
      Various envelopes, found in the drawer of Matthew Vassar's desk.
    - Figurine, undated (Box 39)
      Wooden pedestal with carving of a woman in formal dress with two long braids sitting on a stump, one arm missing or broken.
    - Game (3 pieces), undated (Box 1, Section 01)
      Carved, round ivory game in 3 pieces.
    - Gold watch fob (Matthew Vassar's?), undated (Box 46, Section 03)
    - Inkwell, ceramic figurine - bottom half (3 pieces), undated (Box 1, Section 16)
    - Inkwell, ceramic figurine - top half (1 piece), undated (Box 1, Section 17)
    - Kaleidoscope, undated (Box 43)
      White bisque (biscuit porcelain) kaleidoscope painted with floral design.
    - Ladle, undated (Box 1)
      Wooden ladle used at the Vassar Brewery
    - Leather trunk with latch, undated (On shelf)
      Large leather box with lid and latch. "M V" is printed on either side.
    - Letter holder, undated (Box 23)
      Metal, showing days of the week.
    - Letter openers (2), undated (Box 23)
      Wooden letter openers, 2 different lengths.
    - Life preserver, circa 1845 (Box 45)
      Black metal canister, printed on top with: "The Nautilus Life Preserver - Royal Letters Patent"
    - Marble base, undated (Box 1, Section 27)
      Green and white marble base for a figurine or other item.
    - Mash mixer, undated (Box 1)
      Wooden utensil used at the Vassar Brewery
    - Matthew Vassar beer pitcher, 1818 (Box 35)
      White ceramic beer pitcher with gold trim, initialed MV and dated
    - Matthew Vassar beer pitcher, 1818 (Box 36)
    - Matthew Vassar's canes and umbrella, undated (Box 102)
      One umbrella and several canes. One cane "given to Truman J. Backus, received from Rev. G. H. Backus, 1913 Apr 29."
    - Metal trunks (3), undated (On shelf)
      3 metal trunks, 2 with floral designs, 1 printed with "M. Vassar"
    - Nutcracker, undated (Box 42)
      Handheld nut cracker, wood, with handle, carved in the shape of a lion.
    - Pocket watch, undated (Box 1, Section 07)
      Gold pocket watch. Belonged to Matthew Vassar. Front glass is loose and metal frame will not close.
    - Spectacle case (empty), undated (Box 1, Section 20)
      Black leather spectacle case, missing cap.
    - Spectacles, undated (Box 1, Section 21)
      Brass frame with octagonal lenses.
    - Spectacles, undated (Box 1, Section 19)
      Rusted, silver-colored metal frame with oval lenses. Right lens frame is broken and lens has fallen out.
    - Spectacles, undated (Box 1, Section 18)
      Silver-colored metal frame with oval lenses.
    - Spectacles, undated (Box 1, Section 21)
      Silver-colored metal frame with oval lenses. Both lenses cracked.
    - Spectacles in case (3 pieces), undated (Box 1, Section 20)
      Brown leather spectacle case containing rusted black-frame spectacles with oval lenses.
    - Statuette (poss. inkwell stand), undated (Box 40)
      [Brass]; figure (no head) next to barrel
    - Stereoscope, 1867 (Box 81)
      Stereoscope, wood and brass, design of Joseph L. Bates, patented 1867. Owned by Matthew Vassar.
    - Wooden folding mirror, undated (Box 23)
  - Matthew Vassar, Jr.
    - Napkin ring, undated (Box 46, Section 06)
      Silver, inscribed "MV Jr"
    - Watch fob, gold, undated (Box 46, Section 02)
  - Miscellaneous Family Items
    - John Guy Vassar - Watch fob, gold, undated (Box 46, Section 04)
    - Marquis Georges Le Vasseur - Locket, undated (Box 66)
      Large gold locket with portrait of Marquis Georges Le Vasseur, an ancestor of Matthew Vassar, on one side, and an ornate hair knot on the other side. Glass cabochon covering portrait has separated from the locket.
    - Mary E. Atkinson - Cross stitch of Vassar Family Record, 1832 (On shelf)
      Delicate cross stitch of the Vassar Family's genealogical record, including James and Ann Vassar, and their 8 children. Mary E. Atkinson (1822-1834) was the daughter of Keziah Vassar (1799-1834) and William B. Atkinson, and Matthew Vassar's niece.
    - Portrait of A. J. Downing, undated (Box 19)
      [Watercolor] in ornate gold frame
    - Scarf, undated (Box 9)
      Crimson, floral embroidery.
    - Straight razor, whalebone handle, circa 1890 (Box 82)
      Metal straight razor with whalebone(?) handle, manufactured by Clauss Barber Special in Fremont, Ohio. "M. Vassar" is etched into the handle, but the manufacturing dates of the razor mean that it could not have belonged to either Matthew Vassar or Matthew Vassar, Jr.
- Series II. Vassariana, 1861-2020
  - Accessories
    - Fan, 1871 (Box 83)
      White fan used at graduation by Mary Crockerhouse (VC 1871)
    - Parasol, undated (Box 103 (Roll Box))
      VC reunion parasol, red paper and bamboo
  - Awards and Commemorative Objects
    - Commemorative cup, Frances A. Wood, silver, 1910 (Box 2)
      tall silver cup with lid and handles, inscribed to VC Librarian Frances A. Wood.
    - Key to Miami-Dade County, Florida, circa 1990s (Box 25)
      Key to Miami-Dade County given to Frances Fergusson, housed in original black box
    - Philalethean Society Cup, silver, 1869 (Box 2)
      Philalethean Society cup - silver three-handled. Presented to the Philalethean society for excellence in literary competition.
    - Souvenir bowl, silver, [1896?] (Box 66)
      Ornate silver bowl, gifted to the Class of 1896 from the Class of 1871. Inscribed to: "Grandaughters of Vassar College. Souvenir from '71. 1871 - 1896"
    - Trophy Cup, silver, 1916 (Box 2)
      Silver trophy cup with handles from ANCM Intercollegiate Competition Plays. Won by Vassar Miscellany in 1917.
    - Vase, 1935 (Box 2)
      Silver vase, inscribed to Mary R. Sanford (VC 1892) from a classmate
  - Badges
    - VC Badge, 1933 Aug 26 (Box 67)
      VC "Neighbors' Day" badge welcoming FDR
    - VC Badge, undated (Box 67)
      Violet Barnard's VC Reunion Badge. Large sunflower, made of something organic.
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, 1915 (Box 61)
      Badge owned by Dorothea Anne Harnecker (VC 1919), no ribbon
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, blank, 1915 (Box 22, Slot 10)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1867", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 06)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1869", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 15)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1873", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 19)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1875", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 18)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1884", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 05)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1894", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 37)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1896", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 20)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1897", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 36)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1901" (2), 1915 (Box 22, Slot 12)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1904", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 01)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1904", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 17)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1908", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 14)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1910", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 02)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1910", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 09)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1911", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 08)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumna 1912", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 11)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, Alumnae badges from various years, blank (11), 1915 (Box 61)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumnae Committee - Mabel B. Watson", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 29)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Alumnae Committee - Mrs. A. T. Hadley 1883", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 27)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Charles Swift", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 21)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, Committee Member (4), 1915 (Box 61)
      Blank faculty committee member badges, 3 without medals
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Delegate - "A. T. Hadley", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 27)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "E. H. Haight", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 31)
      Gold, blank, with no medal
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Faculty Committee - A. Underhill", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 24)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Faculty Committee - C. E. Furness", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 25)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Faculty Committee - E. H. Haight", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 37)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Faculty Committee - Lucy M. Salmon" (no medal), 1915 (Box 22, Slot 26)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Faculty Committee - Z. L. Thornbury", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 14)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Guest - Alice Beer", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 28)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Guest - H. D. Woodward 1867", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 07)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Guest - Miss Howland", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 20)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Guest - Miss L A Whitney", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 38)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Guest - Mr. Thornbury", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 13)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Guest - Mrs. A. T. Hadley 1883", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 27)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Guest - Mrs. D L. Belding, 1904", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 04)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Guest - Mrs. Henry MacCracken", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 39)
      Worn by the mother of either MacCracken or his wife according to donor.
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Guest - Mrs. Thornbury", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 13)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Guest", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 17)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, Hostess (4), 1915 (Box 61)
      Blank "Hostess" badges, no medals
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, loose medals (13), 1915 (Box 61)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, Misc (5), 1915 (Box 61)
      Miscellaneous named badges, 3 without medals
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, Misc (8), 1915 (Box 61)
      Miscellaneous unnamed badges, "Alumnae Committee," "Student committee," "Guest," and "Student."
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Mr. A. W. Lent", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 09)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, Student (5), 1915 (Box 61)
      Blank "Student" badges, no ribbons
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, Student Delegate (8), 1915 (Box 61)
      Blank student delegate badges, 4 without medals
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Student 1879", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 10)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Student 1916", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 23)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Student 1917", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 22)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Student 1918", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 30)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Student 1918", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 22)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, "Student 1919", 1915 (Box 22, Slot 03)
    - VC Badge - 50th Anniversary, Trustee (7), 1915 (Box 61)
      Blank trustee badges, most with paper backing board.
  - Banners and Flags
    - Banner, circa 2005 (Box 17)
      Souvenir banner, wooden dowel and white fabric. On one side is Greek flag, on the reverse is Greek writing, a clover and "1908"
    - Banner, undated (Box 59)
      Felt banner, gray with pink lettering and border, which reads "When better men are made Vassar women will make them."
    - Banner, circa 1961 (Box 105 (Oversize))
      Gray and rose felt wall hanging reading: "When better men are made Vassar women will make them."
    - Banner, Class of 1910, undated (Box 7)
      Pink/red felt with white numbers
    - Banner, VC-Yale, undated (Box 59)
      Blue felt banner with white letters: "For God For Country For Yale And For Vassar
    - Banners, Reunion, undated (Box 85 (Oversize))
      Banners used during reunions, mostly felt. Classes of: 1922, 1926, 1927
    - Banners, Reunion, undated (Box 86 (Oversize))
      Banners used during reunions, mostly felt: Classes of 1931 and 1932.
    - Banners, Reunion, undated (Box 106 (Oversize))
      Banners used during reunions, mostly felt. Classes of 1936, 1937, 1941, 1942, and 1947
    - Flag, undated (Box 91 (Oversize))
      American flag, embroidered with "Gift of '67"
    - Flag, 1917 (Box 48)
      Class of 1910 WWI service flag.
    - Flag, undated (Box 32)
      Miniature rose and grey Vassar flag
    - Flag, undated (Box 32)
      Miniature yellow flag with 1904 written in black
    - Flag, undated (Box 51)
      VC flag, rose and grey silk flag in black wooden wand
    - Flag, undated (Folio Room)
      Satin rose and grey flag with gold fringe.
    - Pennants (11), undated (Box 105 (Oversize))
      Felt VC pennants in assorted sizes
    - VC banner, circa 1923 (Box 89 (Oversize))
      Leather banner embossed with Vassar College seal.
    - VC Leather banner, circa 1906 (Box 104 (Oversize))
      Brown leather banner (?) with "Vassar" sewn on it in a lighter color leather.
    - VC seal embossed on a piece of leather, undated (Box 48)
      VC seal embossed on a piece of leather
  - Bookmarks
    - Bookmark, silver, undated (Box 83)
      Sterling, dagger-shaped bookmark with oak leaf motif. Inscribed with initials and "91." Probably belonged to a member of the class of 1891.
    - Bookmark, silver, 1896 (Box 54)
      Sterling bookmark engraved "'94 to '96". Belonged to Sarah Hartzell Fish (1896), who attended Vassar 1892-1896.
    - VC bookmark, undated (Box 66)
      Small metal bookmark, brass-colored with red text reading: "VC Libraries"
  - Ceramics
    - Ceramic coffee cup, undated (Box 4)
      Dresden coffee (espresso?) cup, small blue demitasse with image of VC main building
    - Ceramic cup and saucer, 1910 (Box 27)
      White teacup and saucer with gold edging. From Senior Parlor
    - Ceramic cups and saucers (3), 1911 (Box 27)
      Cream teacups and saucers with gold scalloped edging and Vassar College seal. From Senior Parlor
    - Ceramic dish, Main Building, undated (Box 14)
      Square ceramic dish with an illustration of Main Building on the front. Back reads: "Italy P. V. 07089 Main Building Vassar College"
    - Ceramic dish, Main Building, undated (Box 21)
      Small white ceramic dish with gold trim and an image of VC's Main Building, made for G. W. Halliwell in China
    - Ceramic dish, Main Building, undated (Box 21)
      Blue ceramic dish with gold trim and an image of VC's Main Building, made for John B. Flagler in Germany
    - Ceramic dish, Main Building, undated (Box 62)
      Small ceramic dish with image of VC's Main building
    - Ceramic dish, Poughkeepsie Bridge, undated (Box 62)
      Small ceramic dish with image of Poughkeepsie bridge
    - Ceramic hot water bottle, [circa 1875?] (Box 4)
      Belonged to Lydia M. Patchen, Prep 1873-1875
    - Ceramic mug, 1895 (Box 4)
      Stoneware, beige, handmade mug made by Anne Dorrance (VC 1895) and inscribed with signatures of her VC classmates.
    - Ceramic mug, 1944 (Box 4)
      Large, white mug with gold trim and handle, and gold seal of Vassar College. Class mug? Stamped with "Belleek Willets."
    - Ceramic mug, circa 2007 (Box 14)
      Black souvenir VC mug with gold and maroon decorations
    - Ceramic mug, 1895 (Box 69)
      VC Class of 1895 Mug with signatures
    - Ceramic mug, undated (Box 70)
      Gray mug with pink VC seal and text "Class of 1935"
    - Ceramic mug, undated (Box 70)
      Pink Mug with gray Vassar seal - Reunion favor, Class of 1922
    - Ceramic mug (2), undated (Box 70)
      White mug with gold rim, pink and grey Vassar seal, and words "Vassar College"
    - Ceramic plate, circa 1964 (Box 18)
      Plate, cream ceramic with gold trim and Vassar seal in hot pink and pale gray. Underside printed with "Decorated especially by Laura K. Firth, American Decorators, Inc. Trenton, NJ"
    - Ceramic plate, undated (Box 18)
      Plate, white ceramic with blue glaze, image of The First Collegiate School at Poughkeepsie. Royal Doulton Pottery.
    - Ceramic plate, undated (Box 18)
      Plate, white ceramic with blue glaze, image of The Livingston House at Poughkeepsie. Royal Doulton Pottery.
    - Ceramic plate, undated (Box 18)
      Plate, white ceramic with blue glaze, image of the Van Kleeck House, Poughkeepsie. Royal Doulton Pottery.
    - Ceramic plate, undated (Box 21)
      white and pink ceramic plate with an image of VC's Main Building, made for George W. Halliwell in Bavaria
    - Ceramic plate, undated (Box 31)
      White ceramic plate with blue glaze, "Views of Poughkeepsie, NY - Main Entrance of Vassar College." Printed with "England" on back.
    - Ceramic plate, undated (Box 21)
      White ceramic plate with gold trim and lace-like edge, printed with an image of VC's Main Building, made in Germany
    - Ceramic plate, Class of 1959, 2009 (Box 82)